So here's a summary of what we do in machine learning.
下面总结下机器学习的过程
首先用训练数据训练一堆模型
First, we train a bunch of models with our training data.
然后使用交叉验证数据挑选最佳模型
Then, we use a cross-validation data to pick the best of these models.
And finally, we test it with the testing data to make sure our model is good.
最后 使用测试数据测试模型是否很好
下面举个训练逻辑回归模型的例子
So here's an example of training a logistic regression model.
Let's say, we have four candidates,
假设有四个模型
第一个是一次模型
we train a model of degree one,
which is a line and one of degree two, three, and four.
是一条直线 然后是二次 三次 四次
我们使用训练数据训练它们
We train them with the training data to find
并算出多项式的斜率和系数等等
the slope and the coefficients of the polynomials et cetera.
然后使用交叉验证数据计算所有这些模型的 F1 得分
Then we use the cross-validation data to calculate say the F1 score of all these models.
然后选择 F1 得分最高的模型
And then, we pick the model with the highest F1 score.
最后 使用测试数据确保模型效果很好
As a final step, we use our testing data to make sure our model is good.
So the parameters of the algorithm in this case are the coefficients
因此这里的算法参数就是多项式的系数
但是多项式的次数就像物性参数
of the polynomial but the degree of the polynomial is like a matter parameter.
我们称之为超参数
We call those hyper parameters.
我们再看一个示例
Let's see another example. Let's say,
we're training a decision tree.
假设我们要训练一个决策树
超参数是什么？
So what are the hyper parameters?
其中一个是深度 假设深度是 1
Well, one of them is depth. Let's say we have one of depth one,
2 3 和 4
two, three, and four.
我们使用训练数据训练深度为 1 2 3 和 4 的
We use the training data to train a bunch of trees of depth one,
决策树
two, three, and four.
参数是树叶和节点等的阈值
So the parameters here are the thresholds in the leaves and the nodes et cetera.
然后使用交叉验证集
Then, we take the F1 score and calculate it on
the cross-validation set on each of these models.
计算每个模型的 F1 得分
并选出效果最好的模型
Then we pick the one that did the best.
And finally, with the testing set,
最后使用测试集
we make sure this model is good.
确保该模型很好
So what happens if we have more than one hyper parameter?
如果有多个超参数呢？
这里只有一个超参数 是深度
Here we only have one which is depth.
如果训练支持向量机呢？
What if we're training a support vector machine?
在支持向量机中 我们有一些超参数
So in an SVM, we as we have some hyper parameters like
the kernel which can be linear or polynomial, for example.
例如内核 可以是线性或多项式
And we also have the gamma parameter,
还有 γ 参数
which if it's small, gives a solutions like this.
如果它很小 则结果是这样的
And if it's large,
如果很大
则结果是这样的
It gives a solution like that.
如何选择最佳内核和 γ 组合？
So how do we pick the best combination between kernel and gamma?
很简单 我们使用网格搜索法
Well, very simple, it's called grid search and it literally just says
也就是制作一个表格并列出所有可能的组合 然后选择最佳的组合
make a table with all the possibilities and pick the best one.
这里的列是可以使用的不同内核 包括线性或多项式
Our columns here are the different kernels we can use, linear and polynomial.
行是不同的 γ 值
And the rows are the different values of gamma.
It's recommended to take a few values that grow exponentially such as 0.1,
建议设置几个按指数级增长的值 例如 0.1
1 10 100 1000 等等
1, 10, 100, 1000, etc.
So again, we use our training set to train a bunch of
我们使用训练集训练多个
linear models and polynomial models with different values of gamma.
具有不同 γ 值的线性模型和多项式模型
Then we use the cross validation set to calculate the F1 score on all these models.
然后使用交叉验证集计算这些模型的 F1 得分
And then we simply pick the one with the highest F1 score.
并选择 F1 得分最高的模型
And finally, we use a testing set to make sure that what we did was good.
最后 使用测试集检测所选的模型效果是否很好